

Project Coordinator cum Analyst with **5 years** of Project management experience in the IT sector in both Product based and service based. Proven track record in monitoring, tracking, and managing Project management office activities and in the execution of deliverables.

## Skills

**Key skills** Project control, Monitoring, Management, Execution, and Client servicing.

Visualization M.S. Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Excel Charts

Tools M.S. office, MS Teams, MS Azure, Azure DevOps

### **Certifications and Awards**

- Introduction to Project Management by Simplilearn
- IBM Python for Data Science and AI certification
- Completed Data Science certification course on LinkedIn

# **Experience**

March 2022 - Present

#### **BPK Tech, Hyderabad** – Project Coordinator

- Acting as a liaison between the product owner and the technical team in delivering the project
- Responsible to handle multiple projects for a single client and multiple customers
- Responsible to execute the project in Agile methodology and deliver the requirements with proper sprint and release planning
- Responsible for Scrum ceremonies mainly planning, daily stand-up, Retro, and review meetings
- Conducting daily standup meetings, identifying and removing the impediments
- Creating Azure Dashboard to reflect the progress of the project
- Implementing the corrective measures on board as well as modifying documentation to ensure it is relevant and updated.
- Responsible to manages the scope change process: identifies and anticipates risks and issues, facilitates resolution, mitigation, and appropriate escalation.

April 2021 - March 2022

### **SynapseIndia**, **Noida** – *Project Coordinator*

- Keeping a Track record of Project Management Activities like timelines and ensuring the project execution is going as per the scope of work.
- Responsible to deliver the project with the desired effort, cost, quality, and schedule.

- Also responsible for effectively managing customer expectations and successfully executing the projects.
- Doing regular communication with clients over email and call on day to day basis for requirement gathering/ clarification on the running project.
- Responsible for handling the project from beginning to project delivery.
- Assigning the tasks to different teams as per scheduled time.
- Accountable for chasing the client to ensure the project is running and receiving payment as per agreed terms.
- Coordinating with the development team to ensure regular deliveries are sent to clients.
- Tracking and motoring project activities and resources.
- Conduction regular audits related to each project.
- Responsible for certation, maintenance, and updating project-related documents.

Aug 2019 - March 2021

#### **MetLife GOSC**, **Jaipur** – *IT Project Coordinator*

- Assisting The Project Manager with the coordination of resources, meetings, and information.
- Responsible for handling the project from beginning to project delivery.
- Assigning the tasks to different teams as per scheduled time.
- Responsible to Maintain and monitor The IT Project with the goal of getting them on time.
- Tracking and motoring project activities and resources.
- Tasks include Event handling and Change Management.
- Managing a Master Data record and generating different reports from it.
- Prepared various Visualization in Excel for the month-on-month business report.
- Worked closely with the engineering and business team using scrum/agile methodology

Jan 2018 - July 2019

#### GirnarSoft, Jaipur $-\Im r$ . Analyst

- Closely worked with Data Team for ETL analysis on Data received from a website and social media platforms, then putting all this data into a centralized database called LMS.
- Extracting the data for the tool to analyze and then maintaining and publishing Data Reports.
- Understand the business using received data, and after that maintain and publish Data Reports.
- Coordinating with Teammates for the Data to analyze and present the same for improvement.
- This helps in maintaining a good relationship with existing clients as well as in making new customers.
- Ability to manage multiple projects & clients.

## **Education**

Sep 2011 - May 2015

NIT, Arunachal Pradesh - Bachelor in technology-ECE

7.79 CGPA